<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Emmanuel Momoh</title>
    <link>https://nuel000.github.io/nuel_portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Emmanuel Momoh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 11:14:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuel000.github.io/nuel_portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cryptocurrency-ETL-Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://nuel000.github.io/nuel_portfolio/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuel000.github.io/nuel_portfolio/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>In this project, I employed the use of an automated library called Playwright to extract data from Coin Market Cap. The extracted data was then processed and diligently saved into a MYSQL Database.
See Github repo HERE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Financial Statement Fraud Detection</title>
      <link>https://nuel000.github.io/nuel_portfolio/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuel000.github.io/nuel_portfolio/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>The project&amp;rsquo;s aim was to flag fraudulent financial statements from companies that have been issued a guarantee from an insurance company. The purpose is to ensure the financial information used in the credit risk modelling process is sound.
The deliverables were:
A solution that can handle new incoming data and flag the fraudulent financial statements. Analysis of the predicted fraud across different features. Comparison of the prediction models used. In the course of the project, my team was given a dataset containing financial statements from companies spanning across different industries like construction, logistics etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customers and Products Analysis Using SQL</title>
      <link>https://nuel000.github.io/nuel_portfolio/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuel000.github.io/nuel_portfolio/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this project is to analyze data from a sales records database for scale model cars and extract information for decision-making.
We all know that good analysis starts with questions. Below are the questions we want to answer for this project.
Question 1: Which products should we order more of or less of?🤔
Question 2: How should we tailor marketing and communication strategies to customer behaviors?🤔
Question 3: How much can we spend on acquiring new customers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prosper Loan Data Exploration and Analysis</title>
      <link>https://nuel000.github.io/nuel_portfolio/post/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuel000.github.io/nuel_portfolio/post/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Dataset The data set contains 113,937 loans with 81 variables on each loan, including loan amount, borrower rate (or interest rate), current loan status, borrower income, and many others.The dataset can be found here,with feature documentation available here.
Summary of Findings At the begining of the investigation, I performed preliminary wrangling by converting Income Range and ProsperRating to categorical variable, this returns the income/Prosper rating classes with the categories and orderedness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Analysis on No-show medical appointments</title>
      <link>https://nuel000.github.io/nuel_portfolio/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuel000.github.io/nuel_portfolio/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>In this project, I analyzed a dataset that includes records of over 100,000 medical appointments in Brazil. Specifically focusing on the question of whether or not patients show up for their appointment and finally we will uncover trends and patterns by answering questions such as;
What are the characteristics associated with patients who do not shop up for their appointments? What factors are important for us to know in order to predict if a patient will show up for their scheduled appointment?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://nuel000.github.io/nuel_portfolio/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuel000.github.io/nuel_portfolio/about/</guid>
      <description>I picked interest in data science and analytics in the early months 2022, and in pursuit of this, I took the Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate which exposed me to basic tools for Data Analysis such as SQL, Excel and Tableau.To further cement my understanding of these concepts, applied for and got accepted into ALX-Udacity Data Analytics Nano degree programme which basically delves deeper into use of python for Data Analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://nuel000.github.io/nuel_portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuel000.github.io/nuel_portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Please contact me through any of the social platforms below
Platforms
LinkedIn
Github
Medium
Email : momohemmanuel370@gmail.com</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
